Heat. Heat.
Amen. Church family. Um happy Sabbath.
Um it is uh good to be here [snorts]
with you uh on this beautiful uh Sabbath
day.
Uh [clears throat]
we had a technical difficulty
uh as most of you know. So
uh this is a new uh sermon uh link and
I'm just trying to make sure I got
something up on my screen here. So if
you guys just give me a minute. But um
yeah, today's message uh
is going to be that.
So, so believe that. Hold on one second.
Um all right. [clears throat]
So, let's go ahead you guys. Uh we're
going to um we're going to start with
prayer
and
Okay.
Yep. I'm unable to see my screen right
now. So,
I'm not sure what's going on here, but
I'm going to ask the team if they can
jump in the reream and see what's
happening. Uh because I cannot see
anything. Um but put a one in the chat
you guys if you hear me.
Uh,
well, I'm not even seeing my comments.
Okay. Okay. So, I think a comment just
came through. Um, all right. Let's go.
Let's begin. Heavenly Father,
[clears throat] I want to thank you,
Lord, uh, for just giving us um your
your word today. Lord, I thank you for
the word you're about to feed your
people. I thank you for your truth. I
thank you for your spirit. I thank you
for your love, Lord. Lord, please speak
through me as um as this message is
being shared, Lord. May may lives be
changed. May minds be open. May hearts
be receptive.
We pray this in Jesus name. Amen. And
amen. Um,
all right. So guys, um,
I'm still trying to get my slides up.
Um, and I don't think I have the correct
link, believe it or not. Um, because I
cannot see my screen,
but we're just going to go for this.
We're going to go for this. Y'all put a
one in the chat if you see me. and put a
one in the chat if you could see my
slides on the screen. I just want to put
one slide up, the the uh title slide and
uh see if you guys can uh see that link.
I see my slides. All right.
Okay, there we go. All right.
In the beginning, in the beginning,
today's message, beloved, begins in the
beginning. It begins with the beginning
and uh it is found our opening text is
found in Genesis
chapter 1. Genesis chapter 1 and verse
one. Genesis chapter 1 verse one. The
Bible says
um in the beginning
in the beginning God created the heaven
and the earth.
In the beginning God created the heaven
and the earth. Now
very simple verse but very powerful
verse.
And we are going to be spending
[clears throat and cough]
our time
locked in on this verse.
In the beginning, God created the
heavens and the earth.
Um,
this text is significant because what
we're going to see is that
it is the seed of so much else in the
Bible.
Um, it is the seed
that allows us to understand
who God is and what God does.
In the beginning,
God created the heaven and the earth.
That word beginning simply signifies
the the earliest starting point of time.
Before anything ever was,
there was God.
And I [clears throat] want you to note
with me that this is the reason why
Jesus calls himself the alpha.
In Revelation 1:8, he says,"I am the
Alpha and Omega, the beginning and the
ending, sayeth the Lord, which is and
which was and which is to come, the
Almighty."
Again, in Revelation 1:1,
uh Jesus speaking, saying, "I am Alpha
and Omega, the first and the last." In
Revelation 21:6, he said unto me, "It is
done. I am Alpha and Omega, the
beginning and the end. And in Revelation
22:13,
I am Alpha and Omega, the be the
beginning and the end, the first and the
last. Jesus here is clearly
distinguishing himself from all other
creation by saying, I am the beginning
and the end. I am the alpha and the
omega.
In Psalm chapter 90 verse two, Psalm
chapter 90 verse2 uh the Bible tells us
that before the mountains were brought
forth orever thou hast formed the earth
and the world even from everlasting thou
art God. Thou art God. Please understand
that Jesus that God was before all
things.
God was before all things. Put a one in
the chat if you're following me so far.
Very simple points, but extremely
important points that I want you to
understand and I want you to grasp as we
move forward in this message. Continuing
on in the book of Proverbs chapter 8,
speaking of this uh uh uh Jesus being
before all things, the Bible tells us in
Proverbs chapter 8 verse 22, "The Lord
possessed me in the beginning of his way
before his works of old. I was set up
from everlasting from the beginning
orever the earth was. When there was no
depths, I was brought forth. When there
was no fountains abounding with the
waters, before the mountains were
settled, before the hills was, I was
brought forth. Proverbs 28:26 continues,
"While as yet he had not made the earth,
nor the fields, nor the highest part of
the dust of the world. When he prepared
the heavens, I was there. When he set a
compass upon the face of the depth, when
he established the clouds above, when he
strengthened the fountains of all the
deep,
>> [clears throat and cough]
>> When he gave to the sea his decree
that the waters should not pass his
commandment, when he appointed the
foundations of the earth, then I was by
him as one brought up with him, and I
was daily his delight, rejoicing always
before him.
The text is letting us know that before
anything, Jesus was. Before anything,
God was God is the beginning. You'll
remember John chapter 1, beginning with
verse one, the Bible says, "In the
beginning was the word, and the word was
with God, and the word was God." He was
he he was with God in the beginning.
Through him were all things made and
without him was not was nothing made
that was made. In other words, beloved,
the text is letting us know that God is
the beginner. The originator.
Jesus is the beginner. The originator.
Now, please hold that thought in your
mind for a moment. And I want to notice
the next thing the text says because in
Genesis 1:1 it says in the beginning God
created. God created.
Now that word create it means to make to
fashion to form. The verb especially
implies creation ex nilo
meaning
from nothing or bringing about something
of something new and distinct often by
divine action. It is frequently though
not exclusively used with God as the
subject. So in [clears throat] the text
the Bible is telling us that God created
in the beginning God created and he
created from nothing. He created from
nothing. Now it is unfortunate I cannot
see the chat. So you and I are not going
to be able to dialogue today. So I'm
just going to pray and hope that y'all
follow me because when I say put that
one in the chat, I'm not seeing
anything. when I say put that two in the
chat. So, I'm just going to pray that
y'all follow me, okay? Follow carefully,
you guys. God created from nothing. And
how did he create from nothing? This the
book of Psalms, uh Psalms chapter, I'm
sorry, Genesis chapter 1 tells us this.
It says, "And the earth was without form
and void, and darkness was upon the face
of the deep, and the spirit of God moved
upon the face of the waters." In other
words, when we say that God created
exhils
that there was nothing there, the earth
was without form and void and it was
full of darkness. And this God creates
out of nothing. How does he create? The
Bible tells us in Psalm 33:es 6 and N by
the word of the Lord the heavens were
made. Their starry host by the breath of
his mouth for he spoke and it came to
be. He commanded and it stood firm. He
commanded and it stood firm. He created
by his word. And so beloved, it is not
coincidental that the first book of the
Bible is literally called Genesis in the
Greek. It means origin. It means source
of creation. Genesis
reveals
that God is the originator. He is the
genesis, the generator of the universe,
the generator of the world. And
[clears throat] that generation, the
generation that God does, comes from
nothing.
This is why the Bible says in Hebrews
11:3, "Through faith, we understand that
the worlds were framed by the word of
God, so that things which are seen were
not made of things which do appear." In
other words, God didn't take already
existing substance and then shape it
into something. He created it out of
nothing. He created it out of things
which did not appear which means
nothing. God created out of nothing. Now
what this tells us beloved is that this
world is a supernatural phenomenon.
God spoke it into existence. Now here's
something very interesting I want you to
lock in on for a moment.
>> [clears throat]
>> Evolution
and atheism teaches that the that the
earth is selfgenerated.
In other words, it produced itself. They
don't believe in a creator god. They
believe that the world came about on its
own. And in this sense, earth almost
becomes like God. Creation is God.
The view of of evolution and and atheism
says earth was self-created. The things
that exist came from itself,
self-generated
through natural processes, not nothing
supernatural. These are all natural
processes.
Now, I want you to understand this
because beloved, [clears throat] what
you believe about the creation of the
world can make all the difference in the
world. Because either the world was
supernaturally created or the world was
self-generated
create uh brought about through natural
laws. Why does this make all the
difference in the world? I will tell you
why. Because today, beloved, I'm not
going to be speaking to you about
evolution
per se, even though I I am going to
address that in some sense. But I need
you to understand, beloved, the salvific
nature of this message today.
You see, we just read in Genesis chapter
1 verse one, three things. In the
beginning, God created and he created
the heavens and the earth. And I want to
suggest to you today that you and I are
called to experience
Genesis.
We are called to experience
this very Genesis. Let me show you. The
Bible tells us. The Bible tells us in 2
Corinthians 5:17,
"Therefore, if any man be in Christ, he
is a new creation. The old has passed
away. Behold, the new has come."
Please understand
that the same God that created the
heavens and the earth back there before
anything was made, that same God desires
to create you in his image, to create
you as a new creation.
He desires for you to have your own
Genesis
account. So the question then becomes
how do I experience this Genesis
account? How does it start? How does it
begin? And the answer beloved is found
right here in John chapter 1 verses 1-3
where again we read in the beginning
was the word and the word was with God
and the word was God. It is by the word
of God. The same word of God that was
the active agent in creation back there
before anything was is the same word of
God that is supposed to change us into
new creations.
I'm going to say put a one in the chat
if you're following me so far. I cannot
see it, but I trust that ones are coming
up in the chat right now. Now, this is
just setting the foundation for what
we're going to see in Genesis 1 verse
one. Because what we now need to
understand, beloved,
is that when that word God is used in
Genesis 1:es 1 verse one, the word there
God symbolizes the plural form of the
word God, Elohim. In other words, in
other words,
this verse is the first hint at the
triune God. Let us make man in our image
and in our likeness,
father,
son, and holy spirit.
So then when you see that that that that
God is mentioned in Genesis chapter 1
verse verse one and we remember that
according to John chapter 1 verse 1-3
the word the word was with God and we
see in Genesis
Genesis chapter 1 verse 2 Genesis
chapter 1 verse two that that the spirit
of God moved upon the face of the
waters. Beloved, here in Genesis chapter
1, the first few verses, we have God the
Father, God the Son, which is the word,
and God the Spirit moving upon the face
of the waters,
the triune
God, the Godhead, the divine Godhead.
What does this say to us, beloved?
Here's what it says. When you are born
again or recreated,
it is a threefold birth. It is a
threefold creative process. Let me show
you. For example,
1 Peter chapter 1 vers 23 tells us,
being born again, that's our beginning,
not of corruptible seed, but of
incorruptible by the word of God which
liveth and abideth forever. We are to be
born of the word of God. And the word of
God is Jesus manifest in the flesh. It
is Jesus taking flesh upon. So in other
words, Jesus as one of the three
creating creating uh uh agents or agents
in the creation account. We are to be
born again of the word of God. And what
does it mean to be born of the word of
God? The book of Matthew 4:4 tells us,
"Man shall not live by bread alone, but
by every word that proceedth out of the
mouth of God." To be born of the word of
God is to abide by the word of God. Let
me say it again. To be born of the word
of God is to abide by the word of God.
That's what it means to be born of the
word. It means you are you are abiding
by the word. You are living by the word.
The Bible tells us in Psalm 119 105,
"Thy word is a light is a lamp unto my
feet and a light unto my path." So to be
born of the word means that I am
following the word. I abide by the word.
The word takes precedent in my life. But
we are not only to be born of the word.
We are also to be born of the spirit.
Yes. Yes. Yes. The Bible tells us in
John chapter 3:5, Jesus answered,
"Verily, verily, I say unto thee, except
a man be born of water and of the
spirit, he cannot enter the kingdom of
God." So
the bornagain man is not only born of
the word,
meaning he abides by the word, he is
also born of the spirit. John chapter
3:6 says, "That which is born of the
flesh is flesh, and that which is born
of the spirit is spirit." Well, what
does it mean to be born of the spirit?
To be born of the spirit means that the
fruit of the spirit is being manifested
in your life. But the fruit of the
spirit, Galatians 5:22 and 23 says, is
love, joy, peace, longsuffering,
gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness,
temperance. Against such there is no
law. Thus, beloved, we now see
that the bornagain person just as the
world in its creative as it was being
created is created not just by the
father, not just by the son, not just by
the spirit, but all three working
together. In the same way, the
recreative process of of of us as
individuals must take place under this
threefold partnership.
Not only are to be born of the word, not
only are we be to be born of the spirit,
but check this out everybody. In John 1
12 and 13, the Bible says, "But as many
as received him, to them gave he power
to become the sons of God, even to them
that believe on his name, which were
born not of blood, nor of the will of
the of the flesh, nor of the will of
man, but of God."
Wow. So, we got to be born of the word.
We've got to be born of the spirit. And
we've got to be born of the will
of God. Wow. The will of God. That is
the father. It is his will that we are
born again. But watch this. To be born
of the father, to be born of the father,
to be born of the word, to be born of
the spirit signifies something very,
very, very powerful that I need y'all to
catch. You see beloved, in Philippians
2:13, the Bible says, "For it is God
which workketh in you both to will
and to do of his good pleasure."
To be born of God means that you will to
do his good pleasure.
And you can't will that on your own.
That is the will of God.
So that when you are born of God, uh h
as Psalms 40:8 says, this verse becomes
a reality in you, I delight to do thy
will, oh my God. Yay, thy law is within
my heart. So watch this then. The
threefold evidence of being born again,
of the Father and of the Son and of the
Holy Spirit, is that you delight
to do the word
and you bear fruit as a result of it.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you're
following. Put a five in the chat if
you're following the threefold bornagain
experience. Born of the father, born of
the will of God, born of the word, born
of the spirit means that you delight to
do the will of God. You obey the word of
God and the fruit of the spirit is
manifested in your life. Now, now
as we set that foundation, here is what
I need you to understand, beloved.
the creation
of the world. [clears throat]
Man, I wish I could see these slides. I
mean, not slides. Man, I wish I could
see your re your response right now. But
I'm going to be deprived of that
privilege because I can't see what's
happening in the chat. But listen to me,
y'all.
This creation of the earth was not made
with preexisting
material.
I'm going to let y'all sit with that for
a second and I I'm about to try to see
if I can Yes. There we go. There we go.
There we go.
>> [clears throat]
>> So, let me say it again.
The creation of the earth was not made
with preexisting
material.
Y'all remember that, right? In the
beginning, God created. And what did he
create from?
He created from what?
from nothing.
Yes.
Yeah. He created from nothing. He
created from nothing. So I want you to
reme remember this, beloved. Remember
when God recreates you,
he's not reshaping you out of something
you were before.
He is creating you out of nothing.
Because you remember,
[clears throat and cough] you understand
that before Christ comes into our life,
we are nothing. We have nothing.
[clears throat]
The fool has said in his heart, "There
is no God. Corrupt are they. They have
done abomin abominable iniquity. There
is none that doeth good."
God looked down from heaven upon the
children of men to see if there were any
that did understand that did see God. Do
you understand this?
There is none good.
There is none good. Jeremiah 17:9 says,
"The heart is deceitful above all things
and desperately sick." Who can
understand it? Desperately wicked. Who
can understand it?
All have sinned and fallen short of the
glory of God. So when you see back there
that God created X nilo, I don't want
you to think, man,
how is God going to make me a happy
person? Cuz he he doesn't have he
doesn't have anything to work with. How
is God going to make me a joyous person?
I'm not naturally joyous. How's God God
going to make me a peaceful person? I
don't have these attributes naturally. I
need you to understand that God doesn't
need you to have those attributes
naturally.
God can create from nothing, y'all.
God can create from nothing.
Isaiah 64:6, "But we all are are an
unclean thing, and all our righteousness
as filthy rags, and we all do fade as a
leaf, and our iniquity like the wind
have taken us away." Beloved,
God doesn't need any pre-existing
material to make you a loving, kind,
patient, a merciful, long-suffering
person.
He can create from nothing. And so when
you look at your life and you say, "Man,
I have nothing. What can I bring to God?
I have nothing." God doesn't need you to
have something because God creates ex
nahilo. God creates from nothing. In
fact, we read in the book of Romans
4:17, speaking of Abraham's faith, Paul
says, "God gives life to the dead and
calleth into existence the things that
do not exist.
God does not need pre-made material
to do what he needs to do in your life."
Again, 2 Corinthians says, "Therefore,
if anyone is in Christ, he is a new
creature." This is God saying to you,
listen, I am capable of creating you a
new ex nahilo,
beloved. That is good news.
Because if you're wondering how can God
make me into a new creature, into
something I'm not, he said, listen,
don't worry. Look at what I did back at
creation.
Look at what I did back at creation.
I got you.
So now remember this. Remember what we
learned. What did we see about God in
the beginning? We saw that in the
beginning was before anything was made.
And we saw that that led us to the
conclusion that this is why God says I
am. This is why Jesus says I am the
alpha.
And so now here's what I need you to
understand, beloved, that Jesus is the
alpha of our righteousness.
He is the generator of our
righteousness. He is the genesis of our
righteousness. In the beginning, in your
beginning, God, those four words, in the
beginning, God become everything for the
believer.
is God in your beginning.
In the beginning, God, he is the
generator.
He is the genesis. He is the alpha. So
now let me ask you a question.
Who created the heavens and the earth?
Who created it?
We already have the answer, right? God,
father, son, holy spirit.
God, let us create. Let us make man in
our image. God created it. So, so if God
created it, the question is how? How did
he create it? Through natural means
or was it supernatural?
H was the earth selfgenerated?
Yes. Was the earth
selfgenerated?
Beloved, if the earth was not
self-generated, how can you and I think
that we can generate our own
righteousness?
I need you to understand, beloved, that
as impossible as it was for the earth to
generate itself, so it is as impossible
for us to generate our own
righteousness. Righteousness must be God
generated.
Evolution and atheism deny the
supernatural nature of creation. They
say, "Oh, it's natural law. It's natural
law."
Many of us think, "Hey, I I feel like
I'm naturally good. God should God
should have me covered."
Beloved, listen to me. The thing that I
need you to understand today, beloved,
is that your righteousness,
if you have it, is supernaturally
generated.
It is God generated. Y'all put a one in
the chat. Put a one in the chat.
It is Godenerated.
Only God, only God can generate
righteousness.
Again, again, Psalm 33:6-9. By the word
of the Lord, the heavens were made.
Their starry host by the breath of his
mouth. For he spake and it came to be.
He commanded and it stood firm. Beloved,
that same word,
we may understand that same principle
when we read in Jude 24, now unto him
that is able to keep you from falling
and to present you faultless before the
presence of his glory with exceeding
joy. The same word that spoke and it
stood firm, stood fast. How many of you
want to learn how to stand fast? How
many of you want to stand fast in your
Christian walk? to stand fast in your
daily trials.
God is trying to help us to understand
that we don't have the power to generate
that kind of power. Do you know what
kind of power it takes to cause the
earth and the stars and the moon and the
sun to stand fast?
That is the exact kind of power
necessary for us to stand fast. And you
and I beloved don't have that kind of
power. This is why our righteousness we
must understand must be Godgenerated,
Christ generated. We cannot
selfgenerate
righteousness.
The Bible tells us in Ephesians chapter
2 and and my apologies, but that text is
is uh is um Jude, not Judges uh 24,
Jude. So, apologies for that for that um
typo. But in Ephesians chapter 2 vers 8
and 9, the Bible says, "For by grace you
are saved through faith, and that not of
your own doing, it is the gift of God,
not a result of works, so that no man
may boast."
Y'all catch this
in Philippians 3. And being found in
him, not having a righteousness of my
own that comes from the law, but that
which comes through faith in Christ, the
righteousness from God that depends on
faith. I like how it puts it. Depends on
faith. I'm going to come back to that in
a moment. Titus chapter 3. Titus chapter
3:5. The Bible says he saved us not
because of works done by by us in
righteousness, but according to his own
mercy by washing by the washing and
regeneration and renewal of the Holy
Spirit. So then, beloved, here's what we
see so far. God began the work of
creation.
It was God that did it. God started it.
God was the generator. Now, let me ask
another question. Who continued the
work?
Who continued the work of creation?
I know what you're going to say. You're
going [clears throat] to say, "God
continued it." And then I'm going to
ask, who finished it? Who finished the
creation?
Yeah, you see it on the screen. Genesis
2:1, "Thus the heavens and the earth
were finished, and all the host of
them."
And again they were finished
by the word of God.
God, the father, the son, and the holy
spirit were the active agents in the
work. They finished it. They st they
alpha it and they omegaed it. Now here's
my question for you. Ready? This is a
test question everybody. So pay
attention. Y'all put one in the chat. If
you're ready for the question, you're
going to need to think really hard about
this. Really, really hard. Put a one in
the chat if you are ready for the
question. Put a one in the chat if you
are ready for the question.
So, here's a question. Here's a
question. I know there's a little bit of
delay, but I but I assume I'm I'm going
to see these ones coming in any second.
Here is a question.
How much help
did God
need or get from Adam and Eve in
creating
the world?
How much help
did God the Father and the Son and the
Holy Spirit get
from Adam and Eve in creating the world?
Now, I know what you're going to say,
right? Like, well, Adam and Eve weren't
around until day six. So, okay, God
didn't need their help on day one. He
didn't need their help on day two. He
didn't need their help on day three. He
didn't need their help on day four. He
didn't need their help on day five. But
on day six, he created them. Did he need
their help then? [clears throat]
Not at all.
No help at all.
In [clears throat] fact, in fact, if we
get to Genesis chapter 2:2, the Bible
literally tells us, "And on the seventh
day, God ended his work which he had
made, and he rested on the seventh day
from all his work which he had made."
His work.
Not Adam's work, not Eve's work, his
work.
his work. I need y'all to to let that
sink in. It was his work.
Do you understand what this means for
for you and I, beloved?
God is the originator,
[clears throat] the continuer,
and the finisher. Let's do it this way.
Wherefore, seeing we are all so compass
are all compass about with so great a
cloud of witnesses, let us lay aside
every weight and the sin which does so
easily beset us. And let us run with
patience the the race that is set before
us,
looking onto Jesus, the what everybody?
The what? The author and the finisher of
our faith.
He starts it. He finishes it. He
concludes the work. It's his work.
It's his work.
Let me show you again. Ephesians chapter
2 verse 4-6 through six. But God who in
his rich mercy for his great love
wherewith he loved us even when we were
dead in sins has quickened us together
with Christ by grace are you saved. And
he has raised us up together and made us
sit together in heavenly places in
Christ Jesus that in the ages to come he
might show the exceeding riches of his
grace in his kindness toward us through
Christ Jes Christ Jesus. For by grace
are ye saved through faith and that not
of yourselves. It is a gift of God.
Watch this. Not of works lest any man
should boast. For we are his
workmanship.
We are his [snorts] work
which God created before which God has
before created that we should walk in
them
created in Christ Jesus unto good works.
It's God's work
is God's work. So when the Bible tells
us that he rested on the seventh day
from his work, beloved, I want what I
want you to understand is that the
Sabbath is supposed to be a celebration
of God's work in your life.
The Sabbath is a celebration that I am
the work of God. You are the work of
God.
Again,
how much help did God get from Adam and
Eve in creating anything? What did Adam
and Eve create in that creation process?
Nothing. Nothing. Nothing. Nothing. Now,
follow this. Follow this carefully, you
guys, because I want you to see
something. In Genesis 2:7, the Bible
says, "And the Lord God formed man of
the dust of the ground and breathed into
his nostrils the breath of life, and man
became a living soul. And God, the Lord
God planted a garden eastward in Eden.
So let's say this is the first country.
Let's say Eden is the name of the first
country. So Adam and Eve were
experiencing country living.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand what I mean when I say Adam
and Eve were the first ones to
experience country living. Eden was a
beautiful country setting. The Bible
says there he put the man whom he had
formed and out of the ground the Lord
God out of the ground made the Lord God
to grow every tree which is pleasant to
the sight and good for food, the tree of
life also in the midst of the garden and
also the tree of the knowledge of good
and evil. Okay? And then we're going to
go to Genesis 2:10. Uh and a river went
out of the out of Eden to water the
garden and from then it parted and
became four heads. Now watch this. In in
Genesis 1 vers28, the Bible says, "And
God blessed them," that is the man and
woman. And God said unto them, "Be
fruitful and multiply, and replenish the
earth, and subdue it, and have dominion
over the fish of the sea, and over the
fowl of the air, and over every living
thing that moveth upon the earth." So
check this out, you guys.
After God does all the work, he says to
Adam and Eve, "Y'all have dominion.
H
I don't know. I don't know. I don't know
if you if you're catching this right
now. God gives them dominion over the
earth as if they created it. As if it
was their work, but it was his work.
Are y'all smiling with me?
God gives them [clears throat]
dominion over the earth
even though he is the one that did all
the work.
Wow.
I need you to understand something,
beloved. [clears throat]
that the righteousness that we have, if
we have it, it is not our own. But God
treats it as though it's ours.
He treats it as a He says, "This is
yours. I've given this to you on your
behalf. You couldn't do it on your own.
You don't have power to do it on your
own. I did it for you. I'm giving it to
you,
you guys. That's absolutely
mind-blowing. That's absolutely amazing.
And now, and now, and now, I need you to
see this. I need you to see this. So,
after God finishes all of this, he says
something very interesting in Genesis
chapter 2:15.
The Lord God took the man and put him in
the garden of Eden to dress it
and to keep it.
After he finished all the work,
[clears throat]
after he had done all the creating that
Adam and Eve could not do on their own,
that they didn't have the power to do,
then he says, "All right, I have
finished the work. Now all I want you to
do is to dress it and keep it."
Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow. Keep what I
have already given you.
Do y'all catch that?
So this word dress, this word dress, it
means to labor, to work, to serve, to
till,
to cultivate.
The work of Adam and Eve was simply to
maintain
what God had given them.
So, Adam and Eve, yeah, you got you got
some work to do. You've got a role to
play. All you got to do, listen, you
don't need to create. If I asked you to
do that, you can't create. I'm God. I am
the creator.
But all I want you to do, beloved, is is
just to dress and to keep what I
have given you.
You see this word to keep it means to to
to keep watch to guard, preserve,
observe, protect,
heed, beware, be careful. [snorts] It it
often implies active vigilance and
responsibility. Wow.
Wow. Do y'all see this?
God doesn't say, "I want you to create."
He just says, "Keep
what I have already
given you."
And what I need you to understand,
beloved, is that we cannot keep what we
do not first have.
We cannot keep what we do not first
have.
So the question then becomes, how do I
get the thing that I that God has asked
me to keep? Well, the Bible tells us in
Romans chapter 10:1 17, faith comes by
hearing and hearing by the word of God.
Meaning, I need to have faith
that when the word of God says, I have
made you new and I have given you
everything you need for happiness, for
joy, for peace, for all these things,
you must actually believe it. [cough]
[clears throat]
You must actually
believe it. Remember
through faith we understand that the
worlds were framed by the word of God
that God framed God made these things.
We believe it by faith. We were not
there to see it but we believe it by
faith. In the same way, God is saying to
us, listen, when I tell you that I have
made you righteous,
that I have forgiven you of your sins,
that I have made you a new creature, I
need you to believe it.
I need you to walk in it
as if you believed it were true.
Remember,
remember in the same book of Hebrews
chapter 4, for unto us was the gospel
preached as well unto them, talking
about the children of Israel in the
wilderness. But the word preached did
not profit them, not being mixed with
faith in them that heard it. God says,
"Here's what I need you to do. I need
you to guard the fruit. I need you to
guard the word. I need you to guard the
desire. I have put in you the desire."
Do you believe it?
I have put in you the word. Do you
believe it? I have given you the fruit.
Do you believe it? And if you can say
yes, I believe it and actually mean it.
See, that's the thing.
That's the thing. We can say I believe
it, but our actions don't believe that
we really believe it.
If by faith we can actually grasp, wait
a minute,
the reason why it seems so impossible to
me is because yeah, it is a supernatural
thing.
But if I believe it by faith that God
has supernaturally changed me and made
me turn me from a Saul to a Paul.
If God has supernaturally come into my
life
and said, "I give you my desire.
I give you my word and I'm giving you
the fruit of the spirit." Remember how
God said to Adam and Eve, "You can eat
of all these trees, Zadena." Remember
how you say you can eat of all these
trees, but there's one fruit I don't
want you to eat from.
We might say in essence that that fruit
was the fruit of unbelief. That tree of
the knowledge of good and evil may as
well have represented the fruit of
unbelief because it was Eve's unbelief
that led her to partake of that fruit.
Understand beloved that when God says,
"I've given you my desire." You're born
of the father.
You're born of the word. I've put the
word in you. You are born of the spirit.
I've given you the fruit of the spirit.
Now, he says, I need you to have to by
faith believe it. And then I need you to
guard it. I need you to dress it and
keep it. Remember this, you guys. Watch
this.
Notice how in John 14:15, Jesus didn't
say, "Keep my commandments." He didn't
say, "Keep my commandments." Here's what
he said. He said, "If you love me, keep
my commandments." That that's a whole
different ballgame, you guys. He's not
saying to those who don't know him,
"Keep my commandments." Because they
don't have his commandments. He never
gave it to them. It's not in their
hearts.
Well, why would we why would we love
him? In other words, he says, "Okay, A,
if you love me, B, keep my commandments.
Guard the the the the the implication is
that if you love me, it means I've
already given you something. Now, I want
you to keep it and guard it." Well, why
would we love him? The Bible tells us in
1 John 4:19, we love him because he
first loved us. Okay? So what he's
really saying is, hey, if you understand
that I first loved you, therefore you
will love me. And if you love me, guard
what I've already given you.
What did he give us? Look, Galatians
2:20, I am crucified with Christ.
Nevertheless, I live, yet not I, but
Christ lived in me. And the life which I
now live in the flesh, I live by the
faith of the son of God, who loved me
and gave himself for me. Oh, so we love
him. [clears throat]
because he first loved us
by giving himself for us.
And that's why if we understand that,
then he says, "Keep my commandments."
Then he says, "Keep my commandments."
Watch. Watch what the Bible says. Why
did he give himself for us? He gave
himself for us that that he might redeem
us from all iniquity and purify unto him
a peculiar people zealous of good works.
And how would he do that? The Bible
says, "A new heart will I give you, and
a new spirit will I put within you, and
I will take away the stony heart out of
your flesh, and I will give you a heart
of flesh." So watch this. He says, "I'm
going to give you a new heart, new
desires,
the f the will of the father. I'm going
to give you a new spirit, the Holy
Spirit, the fruit of the spirit. And I'm
going to take away the stony heart out
of your flesh. And I'm going to write my
law, the word of God in your f. That is
the threefold born again experience.
Father, son, holy spirit.
And when the father, son, and holy
spirit come in you to work in you, they
bring everything.
>> [cough]
>> They bring the desire. They bring the
fruit. They bring the word and they give
it to you.
They get, you know, Adam and Eve had no
prior experience in righteousness before
God created them. It's kind of a stupid
statement, right? They had no, it wasn't
like they were righteous and on day six,
he made them and all of a sudden, no,
no, no. He gave everything to them that
they needed for righteousness.
But it would also allow Zadena
the ability for them to not choose
righteousness.
He allowed a tree of the knowledge of
good and evil in the garden because
freedom of choice is the foundation
of love.
And so God says, God says, if I give you
desire and I give you the word and I
give you the fruit, I want you to live
as though those things are real in your
life. And my my my command to you is to
keep those things. I need you to
understand why. Because the so be so the
Bible says be sober, be vigilant because
your adversary the devil as a roaring
lion walketh about seeking whom he may
devour. We find this very principle
right there in Genesis 3:1 where the
Bible says, "Now the serpent was more
subtle than any beast of the field which
the Lord God had made. And he said unto
the woman, "Yay, has God said, do you
really believe
what God said?"
That was the temptation.
[clears throat]
You guys hear me? Testing one, two.
Testing one, two. Testing one, two. Can
you guys hear me now?
I think we're back on.
Put a one in the chat if you can hear
me.
One in the chat if you can hear me.
All right.
Yeah, y'all. Um, my apologies. I don't
know what happened to my uh uh to my
screen just now, but
um
Amen. God is good. God is good. So guys,
listen. I don't know where where what's
the last thing you heard, but I will
simply say this that the temptation of
Adam up given to Eve by the serpent was
to doubt God's word.
If I can get you to doubt that God has
really made you new creation. If I can
get you to doubt that God has really put
his his desire in your heart. If I can
get you to doubt [clears throat] that
that God has already given you the fruit
of the spirit. If I can get you to doubt
that God has given you the word and put
your put his word into your heart. If I
can get you to doubt God's word where it
says you will delight to do my will. If
I can just get you to doubt those
things,
then you eat of the fruit of unbelief.
I want [snorts] to share something with
you as we close.
Don't doubt God's word. Don't doubt his
promises. Don't doubt his power. And
don't don't think that you are supposed
to self-generate righteousness. You
cannot do it. You can only keep what God
has given you. And therefore, beloved,
our prayer ought to be, God, give us,
give us, give me
your righteousness.
And then, Lord, equip me and help me to
guard it, to keep it. Because beloved,
the only thing he requires us to do is
to walk by faith. Believe by faith. And
in believing by faith, you will live out
that fruit. In believing by faith, you
will live out that word. In believing by
faith, you will live out that desire.
It's not just a thing that you say, I
believe. There's no change in the life.
No, God brings that change. And the
evidence that you have been born again,
that threefold birth, the evidence is
that the desire, the word, and the
spirit will be evident in your life.
Beloved,
Paul said these words. He said, "I
rejoice."
He said, "I protest by your rejoicing
which I have in Christ Jesus our Lord. I
die daily.
I die daily. I want to close with this
thought and then we're going to pray.
When Paul said,"I die daily," he was
implying that we must be born again
daily. We must be born again daily.
And what I want you to understand,
beloved, is that every day we have a
genesis.
Every day we have a beginning.
Does your beginning start off with these
four words?
In the beginning,
God.
Because if they start off with those
words, I need you to understand
something. I think of it like this,
beloved. Every day, God invites us to
country living.
Every day, God invites us to live in the
garden,
to to dress and to keep what he has
already provided. And I need you to
understand that the devil's goal every
day is to get you put out of the garden,
put out of the country.
You remember Genesis 3:24, the Bible
says the Lord, the Lord God said,
"Behold, the man has become as one of us
to know good and evil, and now lest he
put forth his hand and take also the
tree of life and eat and live forever."
Therefore, the Lord God sent him forth
from the garden of Eden to till the
ground from whence he from whence he was
taken. So he drove out the man and
placed at the east of the garden of Eden
cherubam and a flaming sword, which
turned every way to keep the way of the
tree of life. I need you to understand
this. Outside of the garden, you till
the ground. Outside of the garden, you
[clears throat] have to work to produce.
Inside of the garden, there's no such
thing. Inside the garden,
you only keep what God has given you.
And I'm telling you, it is a much better
experience
to keep what God has given you
than to be out of the garden and trying
to generate your own fruit,
generate your own righteousness.
So beloved, we can live, we can live our
Christian experience in one of two
places. We can either have country
living, we can by faith be living in
that garden in which God has already
provided everything that we need and
say, "I'm I'mma live in a garden." And
no matter what the devil says, no matter
how he's going to try to lure me out of
the garden or get me to unbelief so I
can get put out of the garden, Lord, I'm
going to stay in the garden. Every day
is like a is like a replay every day.
All right. [clears throat] Are you g are
first of all are you by faith going to
be found in the garden and secondly are
you going to stay in this garden today
or will you be lured out of it by the
enemy of souls. If you are tired of
trying to generate your own fruit.
If you're tired of trying to generate
your own fruit,
I want you to put that one in the chat
and I want you to say I want you to make
that commitment to say, "Lord,
I am done
trying to do the impossible.
I don't have power to create
and righteousness
has to be created
and it is not in me. I have nothing for
you to work with Lord. But the Lord
doesn't need he can create ex nahilo.
So Lord
create in me a new heart, a clean heart
and renew in me a right spirit. And then
Lord remind me
that my only work
is to guard and to keep what you have
already
given me.
If the devil comes not for but for to
kill and steal and destroy,
then Lord, help me to guard
my peace, to guard joy, to guard
longsuffering, to guard gentleness, to
guard goodness. I help me no longer try
to attain goodness, try to attain
gentleness. No, Lord, I believe that by
your word, you said I have it. Now Lord,
teach me to guard it.
Teach me to guard it. If that is your
desire, you want to move from outside of
the garden, digging your own dirt,
trying to produce your own fruit. Lord,
help me every day to live in the garden.
Put that seven in the chat as we close
in prayer. Lord, teach me to live in
paradise now. To live in the garden now.
to experience country living
now.
Heavenly Father, thank you. Thank you
for speaking to us today. Thank you for
feeding us the word. And though Lord, we
had technical difficulties, I pray that
this message will reach every soul that
it needs to reach. Please Lord,
please forgive us for working outside
the garden.
Forgive us for living outside of the
country of Eden. Forgive us for
generating or attempting to generate our
own righteousness. Lord, may we
understand how much of a supernatural
work this is. And may we understand that
the only way we can plug into it is by
faith.
And then Lord, teach us to guard what
you have already given us. Lord,
thank you for your amazing grace. Thank
you, Lord, for doing the work and then
saying to us, "Have dominion."
Lord, we know if it were up to us, we
could have dominion over nothing.
Lord, you said to us,
"Have dominion."
So Lord,
we thank you
for imputing and imparting your
righteousness to us.
May we guard it is our prayer in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen.
May God bless you. Uh may God continue
to draw you closer to him in his
presence. We're going to go ahead and
put the link um uh in the chat for the
altar live. We'll also put up on the
screen um uh our uh QR codes uh for you
to either um uh connect with LOC uh if
you're interested in Bible studies for
baptism. You'll see the QR code there or
you'll see our Bible worker uh contact
information.
If you want to follow us on social
media, you'll see our our QR code there.
I want to again thank you all for tuning
in. Thank you all for uh for bearing
some of the technical difficulties we
had being in different parts of the uh
[clears throat]
of the country today. Atante um uh back
there in Alabama and I'm in Virginia.
Thank you all for uh bearing bearing
with us. And again, may God bless you,
may God keep you, may God empower you,
and may God fill you, may God create you
a new. That's our prayer. That's our
prayer. God bless you and um until next
time.
>> Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at living
manana.urch. We are not just here for
Sabbath service. We have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health, physical health, weekly prayer
service, financial health, and proving
the existence of God. It is our desire
that our programming will continue to
bless you. Please continue to pray for
us as we fulfill God's mission to go
into all the world with the gospel of
Jesus Christ.
Heat. Heat.
[music]
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat. N. [music]
[music]
Heat. Heat.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.
[music]
Heat. Heat.
Wow. [music]
[music]
Heat.
Come
>> [music]
[music]
>> on.
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]
[music] Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[music]